NIKKI PETERSEN

nikkipetersen.dev@gmail.com II 720.883.2420 II Denver/Boulder

www.linkedin.com/in/NikkiPetersenCSM II www.nikkipetersen.dev II github.com/piknikki

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Developer with experience in process improvement, Agile Methodology, business analysis, project management and able to learn technical information quickly while communicating it in an easy to understand language. Self-motivated, solutions-driven, and resourceful problem-solver with superior conflict resolution skills, leadership, and highly effective remote and co-located collaboration skills contributing to strong and agile teams.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript (vanilla and jQuery), Node.js, Express, MongoDB/Mongoose, React, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Firebase, external RESTful APIs, Python, GitHub, Git, Heroku, paired programming, remote work and collaboration, Trello, Postman, Scrum/Agile, Microsoft Suite, Google Suite, Kanban, Lean, XP, QA Testing, JIRA, Confluence, Progressive Web Apps.

APPLICATIONS BUILT

Clicky Game | Solo Developer | https://thawing-caverns-69795.herokuapp.com https://github.com/piknikki/ReactClickGame | A Click Game, utilizing JavaScript, React.js, and Heroku.

Burger App I Solo Developer I https://whispering-spire-37868.herokuapp.com https://github.com/piknikki/burger A categorizing app utilizing JavaScript, Node.js, Express, SQL, and Heroku.

Socially Awkward Gorilla I Solo Developer I https://evening-headland-21699.herokuapp.com https://github.com/piknikki/friendfinder3000

A "friend finder" matching app, utilizing Node.js, Express, and Heroku.

EventSearch | Co-Developer | https://www.nikkipetersen.dev/Project1
https://github.com/piknikki/Project1
An event search app. utilizing Bootstrap, JavaScript iQuery APIs, and

An event search app, utilizing Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, APIs, and Firebase. Responsible for front end, Firebase authentication, Google API.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Development Tutor, Trilogy Education, Denver, CO 6/2019 - Present

- Empower students through teaching, coaching, and mentoring, to achieve best comprehension of software development.
- Create individualized curriculum for each student, based on learning style, subjects of interest, and industry standards.
- Topics include MERN stack, Agile Methodology, and studying/learning techniques.

Donation Center Manager, A Precious Child, Broomfield, CO 11/2017 - 5/2018

 Managed teams of 5-60 volunteers, facilitating daily stand-up meetings, acting as a Servant Leader to multiple self-organizing teams managing multiple concurrent projects, providing support and mentoring to achieve and surpass established daily and monthly goals.

- Utilized Scrum, Lean, and Agile methodologies to continuously improve processes, to increase monthly productivity by 23% and improve quality by 18%.
- Managed multiple warehouses and multiple cross-functional teams, with rapidly shifting priorities — adjusting quickly to changing resources and delegating workloads appropriately to maximize efficiency.
- Constant improvement of team dynamics and performance, with organization-wide coordinated collaboration and diplomatic stakeholder management.

Independent Coach and Entrepreneur, Thornton, CO

1/2016 - 10/2017

- Empowered clients through coaching, to achieve best work as entrepreneurs and double income. Helped clients with a variety of skills, including content marketing and business strategy. Provided guidance, support, and mentoring to clients, applying Lean and Agile business principles.
- Blogged weekly, created and maintained a WordPress website, and self-published a book.

Business Analyst/IT Project Manager, Ralph Henderson, Boulder, CO 1/2006-5/2013

- Effectively advised the CEO of multiple small software companies in Business Analysis and Project Management.
- Developed functional business specifications for new software products, projects, and business analysis in the acquisition of new companies.
- Worked closely with the CEO on multiple day-to-day aspects of the business, spanning strategic planning, leadership team coordination/follow-up, and cross-functional initiatives, to grow businesses from struggling to profitable.

EDUCATION

University of Denver, Denver, CO Full Stack Web Development Certificate, 2019

Scrum Alliance / Mike Cohn, Boulder, CO Certified Scrum Master, 2018

Regis University, Denver, CO

Master of Nonprofit Management — Leadership

Metropolitan State University, Denver, CO Bachelor of Science in Chemistry & Criminal Law

Des Moines University School of Osteopathic Medicine, Des Moines, IA Completed 90% of doctorate degree